For over a decade,
لأكثر من عقد من الزمن،
I have studied young people that have been pushed out of school,
درست الشباب الذين تم طردهم من المدرسة،
so called "dropouts."
ما يسمى بـ"التسريح"
As they end up failed by the education system,
حيث انتهى بهم المطاف بالفشل في النظام التعليمي
they're on the streets where they're vulnerable to violence,
انهم في الشوارع حيث يكونوا عرضة للعنف
police harassment,
مضايقات الشرطة،
police brutality
وحشية الشرطة،
and incarceration.
والسجن
I follow these young people for years at a time,
أنا اتبع هؤلاء الشباب لسنوات
across institutional settings,
عبر الأطر المؤسسية،
to try to understand what some of us call the "school-to-prison pipeline."
لمحاولة فهم ما يطلق عليه بعضنا "خط أنابيب من المدرسة إلى السجن"
When you look at a picture like this,
عندما تنظر لصورة من هذا القبيل،
of young people who are in my study ...
للشباب الذين هم في دراستي ..
you might see trouble.
قد ترى المتاعب.
I mean one of the boys has a bottle of liquor in his hand,
أعني أحد الأولاد كان يحمل زجاجة من الخمر بيده،
he's 14 years old
أنه في الـ 14 من العمر
and it's a school day.
وفي يوم دراسي.
Other people, when they see this picture,
الأشخاص الآخرين عندما يرون هذه الصورة،
might see gangs,
قد ترى العصابات،
thugs, delinquents --
قطاع الطرق، المنحرفين
criminals.
المجرمين.
But I see it different.
لكن أنا أرى الصورة بشكل مختلف.
I see these young people through a perspective
أنا أرى هؤلاء الشباب من خلال منظور
that looks at the assets that they bring to the education system.
يبحث عن الفوائد التي يقدمونها للنظام التعليمي.
So will you join me in changing the way we label young people
لذا هل ستنضمون إليّ بتغيير طريقة تسميتنا للشباب
from "at-risk" to "at-promise?"
من " معرضين للخطر " إلى " مبشرين " ؟
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
How do I know that these young people
كيف لي أن أعلم بأن هؤلاء الشباب
have the potential and the promise to change?
لديهم القدرة والتعهد بالتغيير؟
I know this because I am one of them.
أنا أعلم ذلك لأنني واحد منهم.
You see, I grew up in dire poverty in the inner city,
كما ترون، لقد نشأت في فقر أليم في الأحياء الفقيرة.
without a father --
بدون والد
he abandoned me before I was even born.
لقد هجرني قبل أن أولد
We were on welfare,
لقد كنا بخير،
sometimes homeless,
أحياناً من دون مأوى،
many times hungry.
وأحياناً كثيرة جائعين.
By the time I was 15 years old,
عندما كنت في الـ 15 من العمر،
I had been incarcerated in juvy three times for three felonies.
كنت قد احُتجزت ثلاث مرات لثلاث جنايات.
My best friend had already been killed.
صديقي المقرب تم قتله
And soon after,
في وقت قصير،
while I'm standing next to my uncle,
بينما كنت أقف بجانب عمي،
he gets shot.
تلقى طلقة ناريه
And as I'm waiting for the ambulance to arrive
وبينما كنت بانتظار الإسعاف لتصل
for over an hour ...
لأكثر من ساعة ..
he bleeds to death on the street.
كان ينزف حتى الموت على الشارع.
I had lost faith and hope in the world,
كنت قد فقدت الإيمان والأمل في هذا العالم،
and I had given up on the system because the system had failed me.
و يئست من النظام لأن النظام جعلني أفشل
I had nothing to offer
لم يكن لدي شيء لأقدمه
and no one had anything to offer me.
ولم يكن لأحد أي شيء كي يقدمه لي
I was fatalistic.
كنت هالكاً
I didn't even think I could make it to my 18th birthday.
لم أكن أتصور بأنني سأصل لعيد ميلادي الـثامن عشر.
The reason I'm here today
السبب لوجودي هنا اليوم
is because a teacher that cared reached out
بسبب معلمة مدت يدها إليّ بإهتمام
and managed to tap into my soul.
وتمكنت من الاستفادة من روحي
This teacher,
هذه المعلمة،
Ms. Russ ...
السيدة روس ..
she was the kind of teacher that was always in your business.
لقد كانت مثالاً من المعلمين الذين يتدخلون دائماً في شؤونك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك الحضور)
She was the kind of teacher that was like,
لقد كانت مثالاً من المعلمين
"Victor, I'm here for you whenever you're ready."
" فيكتور، أنا هنا لأجلك متى ما كنت على استعداد "
(Laughter)
(ضحك الحضور)
I wasn't ready.
لم أكن مستعداً
But she understood one basic principle about young people like me.
لكنها كانت تتفهم مبدأ أساسي واحد عن الشباب أمثالي
We're like oysters.
نحن مثل المحار
We're only going to open up when we're ready,
نفتح فقط عندما نكون مستعدين
and if you're not there when we're ready,
واذا لم تكن متواجد عندما نكون مستعدين،
we're going to clam back up.
سنغلق على أنفسنا
Ms. Russ was there for me.
السيدة روس كانت متواجدة لأجلي
She was culturally relevant,
لقد كانت ملائمة ثقافياً،
she respected my community, my people, my family.
احترمت مجتمعي، جماعتي وعائلتي
I told her a story about my Uncle Ruben.
لقد اخبرتها قصة عن عمي روبن
He would take me to work with him because I was broke,
كان يأخذني للعمل معه لأنني مفلس،
and he knew I needed some money.
وكان يعلم بأنني في حاجة للمال
He collected glass bottles for a living.
لقد كان يجمع قناني زجاجية من أجل لقمة العيش
Four in the morning on a school day,
أربعة في الصباح في يوم دراسي
we'd throw the glass bottles in the back of his van,
كنا نرمي القناني الزجاجية في الجزء الخلفي من سيارته،
and the bottles would break.
والزجاجات كانت تكسر
And my hands and arms would start to bleed
و يدي وذراعي تبدآن بالنزيف
and my tennis shoes and pants would get all bloody.
وأحذية التنس وبنطلوني تتلطخان بالدماء
And I was terrified and in pain, and I would stop working.
وقد كنت مذعوراً وأشعر بالألم، و أود أن أتوقف عن العمل،
And my uncle, he would look me in the eyes and he would say to me,
وعمي كان يشاهد عيوني ويقول لي،
"Mijo,
"Mijo,
estamos buscando vida."
estamos buscando vida."
"We're searching for a better life,
" نحن نبحث عن حياة أفضل،
we're trying to make something out of nothing."
ونحاول أن نصنع شيء من لا شيء "
Ms. Russ listened to my story,
استمعت السيدة روس لقصتي،
welcomed it into the classroom and said,
رحبت بها في الفصل الدراسي وقالت،
"Victor, this is your power.
" فيكتور، هذه قوتك
This is your potential.
وهذه هي قدراتك
Your family, your culture, your community have taught you a hard-work ethic
عائلتك، ثقافتك، مجتمعك قاموا بتعليمك أخلاقيات العمل الجاد
and you will use it to empower yourself in the academic world
وسوف تستخدمها لتمكين نفسك في العالم الأكاديمي
so you can come back and empower your community."
حتى تتمكن من العودة وتمكين مجتمعك "
With Ms. Russ's help,
مع مساعدة السيدة روس،
I ended up returning to school.
انتهى بي الأمر بالعودة للمدرسة
I even finished my credits on time
حتى انهيت المواد المقررة في الوقت المحدد
and graduated with my class.
وتخرجت مع فصلي
(Applause)
(تصفيق الحضور)
But Ms. Russ said to me right before graduation,
ولكن السيدة روس قالت لي قبل التخرج،
"Victor, I'm so proud of you.
" فيكتور، أنا فخورة جداً بك
I knew you could do it.
لقد علمت بأنك تستطيع فعلها
Now it's time to go to college."
الآن حان الوقت للالتحاق بالجامعة "
(Laughter)
(ضحك الحضور)
College, me?
الجامعة، أنا؟
Man, what is this teacher smoking thinking I'm going to college?
يا رجل، ماذا تدخن هذه المعلمة كي تفكر بأنني سأذهب للجامعة؟
I applied with the mentors and support she provided,
قدمت طلبي مع التوجيه والدعم من قبلها
got a letter of acceptance,
حصلت على رسالة القبول
and one of the paragraphs read,
و واحدة من الفقرات التي تحتويها كما يلي
"You've been admitted under probationary status."
" لقد تم قبولك تحت وضع المراقبة "
I said, "Probation? I'm already on probation,
قلت: " مراقبة؟ أنا فعلياً تحت المراقبة،
that don't matter?"
هذا لا يهم؟ "
(Laughter)
(ضحك الحضور)
It was academic probation, not criminal probation.
لقد كانت مراقبة اكاديمية وليست جنائية
But what do teachers like Ms. Russ do to succeed with young people
ولكن ماذا يفعل المعلمون أمثال السيدة روس كي ينجحون مع الشباب
like the ones I study?
مثل الذين قمت بدراستهم؟
I propose three strategies.
أقترح ثلاث استراتيجيات
The first:
الأولى:
let's get rid of our deficit perspective in education.
دعونا نتخلص من منظور العجز لدينا في التعليم
"These people come from a culture of violence,
" هؤلاء الناس يأتون من ثقافة العنف،
a culture of poverty.
ثقافة الفقر
These people are at-risk; these people are truant.
هؤلاء الناس معرضين للانحراف، هؤلاء الناس متشردين
These people are empty containers for us to fill with knowledge.
هؤلاء الناس هم حاويات فارغة لنا لملأها بالمعرفة
They have the problems,
هم لديهم المشاكل،
we have the solutions."
ونحن لدينا الحلول "
Number two.
الاستراتيجية الثانية
Let's value the stories that young people bring to the schoolhouse.
دعونا نقدّر القصص التي يأتي بها الشباب للمدرسة
Their stories of overcoming insurmountable odds are so powerful.
قصصهم في التغلب على الصعاب التي لا تقهر قوية جداً
And I know you know some of these stories.
و أعلم بأنكم تعرفون بعضاً من هذه القصص
These very same stories and experiences
هذه القصص والتجارب المتشابهة
already have grit, character and resilience in them.
لديها العزيمة والشخصية والمرونة في نفوسهم
So let's help young people refine those stories.
لذا دعونا نساعد الشباب بصقل هذه القصص
Let's help them be proud of who they are,
دعونا نساعدهم على أن يفخروا بأنفسهم
because our education system welcomes their families, their cultures,
لأن نظامنا التعليمي يرّحب بأسرهم وثقافاتهم،
their communities
ومجتمعاتهم
and the skill set they've learned to survive.
ومجموعة المهارات التي تعلموها من أجل العيش
And of course the third strategy being the most important:
وطبعاً الاستراتيجية الثالثة تعتبر الأهم:
resources.
الموارد
We have to provide adequate resources to young people.
علينا تقديم الموارد الكافية للشباب
Grit alone isn't going to cut it.
العزيمة وحدها لا تكفي
You can sit there and tell me all you want,
بإمكانك الجلوس وتخبرني بكل ما تريد،
"Hey man, pick yourself up by the bootstraps."
" يا رجل، ارفع نفسك عن طريق طوق الحذاء "
But if I was born without any straps on my boots --
ولكن ماذا لو ولدت من دون أي طوق بأحذيتي
(Laughter)
(ضحك الحضور)
How am I supposed to pick myself up?
كيف بإمكاني رفع نفسي؟
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Job training,
التدريب المهني،
mentoring,
التوجيه
counseling ...
تقديم المشورة
Teaching young people to learn from their mistakes
تعليم الشباب بأن يتعلموا من أخطائهم
instead of criminalizing them,
بدلاً من تجريمهم،
and dragging them out of their classrooms like animals.
وسحبهم خارج صفوفهم مثل الحيوانات
How about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
I propose that we implement restorative justice in every high school in America.
أنا أقترح بأن ننفذ عدالة إصلاحية بكل مدرسة ثانوية في أمريكا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So we went out to test these ideas in the community of Watts in LA
لذلك ذهبنا لاختبار هذه الأفكار في مجتمع واتس في لوس انجلوس
with 40 young people that had been pushed out of school.
مع 40 شاب تم طردهم من المدرسة
William was one of them.
ويليام كان أحدهم
William was the kind of kid that had been given every label.
ويليام كان أحد الأطفال الذين يطلق عليهم جميع المسميات
He had dropped out, he was a gang member,
تم تسريحه، كان عضو في عصابة،
a criminal.
مجرم
And when we met him he was very resistant.
وعندما التقينا به كان مقاوماً جداً
But I remember what Ms. Russ used to say.
ولكن أتذكر ماذا اعتادت السيدة روس أن تقول
"Hey, I'm here for you whenever you're ready."
" يا رجل، أنا هنا لأجلك متى ما كنت على استعداد "
(Laughter)
(ضحك الحضور)
So over time --
لذلك مع مرور الوقت
over time he began to open up.
مع مرور الوقت بدأ بالانفتاح لنا
And I remember the day that he made the switch.
واتذكر اليوم الذي بدأ به بالتغير
We were in a large group
كنا في مجموعة كبيرة
and a young lady in our program was crying
وسيدة شابة في برنامجنا كانت تبكي
because she told us her powerful story
لأنها قالت لنا قصتها القوية
of her dad being killed
لوالدها حين تم قتله
and then his body being shown in the newspaper the next day.
وبعد ذلك ظهرت جثته بالصحف في اليوم التالي
And as she's crying, I don't know what to do,
وبينما كانت تبكي، لم أعرف ما يجب القيام به
so I give her her space,
لذلك أعطيتها مساحتها،
and William had enough.
و ويليام كان لديه ما يكفي
He slammed his hands on the desk and he said,
ضرب يديه على الطاولة وقال:
"Hey, everybody! Group hug! Group hug!"
" مهلاً، الجميع! عناق المجموعة! عناق المجموعة! "
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
This young lady's tears and pain turned into joy and laughter
دموع وألم هذه السيدة الشابة تحول إلى فرح وضحك
knowing that her community had her back,
مع علمها بأن مجتمعها في مساندتها
and William had now learned that he did have a purpose in life:
و ويليام تعّلم الآن بأن لديه غاية في الحياة
to help to heal the souls of people in his own community.
بالمساعدة في شفاء أرواح الناس من مجتمعه
He told us his story.
لقد أخبرنا بقصته
We refined his story
لقد أعدنا صياغة قصته
to go from being the story of a victim to being the story of a survivor
وانتقلنا بها من كونها قصة ضحية إلى كونها قصة أحد الناجين
that has overcome adversity.
الذي تغلب على الشدائد
We placed high value on it.
وضعنا قيمة عالية عليها
William went on to finish high school,
ويليام واصل وقام بإنهاء دراسته الثانوية
get his security guard certificate to become a security guard,
وحصل على شهادة حراسة الأمن ليصبح حارس أمن،
and is now working at a local school district.
ويعمل الآن في المدرسة المحلية للحي
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Ms. Russ's mantra --
شعار السيدة روس
her mantra was always,
شعارها كان دائماً
"when you teach to the heart, the mind will follow."
" عندما تعلّم القلب، العقل سيتبعه "
The great writer Khalil Gibran says,
الكاتب العظيم خليل جبران يقول:
"Out of suffering have emerged the greatest souls.
" من المعاناة خرجت أقوى الأرواح "
The massive characters are seared with scars."
" أعظم الوجوه هي تلك المكويّة بالندبات "
I believe that in this education revolution that we're talking about
أؤمن بأن في الثورة التعليمية التي نتحدث عنها
we need to invite the souls of the young people that we work with,
فنحن بحاجة لدعوة أرواح الشباب الذي نعمل معهم،
and once they're able to refine --
وما إن يكونوا قادرين على التحول
identify their grit, resilience and character
قم بتحديد عزيمتهم، مرونتهم وشخصيتهم
that they've already developed --
التي قد تطورت
their academic performance will improve.
أداؤهم الأكاديمي سيتحسن
Let's believe in young people.
دعونا نؤمن بالشباب
Let's provide them the right kinds of resources.
علينا تزويدهم بالأنواع الصحيحة للموارد
I'll tell you what my teacher did for me.
سأخبركم ماذا فعلت معلمتي من أجلي
She believed in me so much
هي وثقت به كثيراً
that she tricked me into believing in myself.
مما جعلني أؤمن بنفسي،
Thank you.
شكراً لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)